<idea-plugin>
    <id>cafe.jeffrey.ide.plugin.idea</id>
    <name>Jeffrey Microscope</name>
    <vendor email="bouda.petr@gmail.com" url="https://jeffrey-analyst.cafe">Petr Bouda</vendor>
    <!-- <version> and <idea-version since-build/> are injected at build time by the IntelliJ
         Platform Gradle plugin's patchPluginXml task (from build.gradle.kts). -->

    <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>Jump from a JFR flame graph straight to your code.</h3>

        <p>
            <b>Jeffrey Microscope</b> is the companion IDE plugin for
            <a href="https://jeffrey-analyst.cafe">Jeffrey</a>, a tool for analyzing Java Flight
            Recorder (JFR) recordings and heap dumps. While you explore a flame graph, a heap-dump
            view, or any other Microscope view, this plugin lets you click a stack frame or a class
            and land on the exact line of source in your already-open IntelliJ window.
        </p>

        <p>
            <b>The plugin is headless</b> — it adds no toolbars, tool windows, or actions of its own.
            It runs quietly in the background and enriches Jeffrey Microscope, letting Microscope
            discover your open IntelliJ projects and either navigate straight to the matching code or
            download the sources back into the application directly.
        </p>

        <p><b>What it does</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Frame-to-source navigation</b> — resolves a fully-qualified class and method to a
                file, line, and column, opens it, and brings the IDE window to the front.</li>
            <li><b>Inline source</b> — serves source text back to Microscope so it can show code next
                to the profile, preferring attached sources over decompiled <code>.class</code> files.</li>
            <li><b>Zero configuration</b> — Microscope discovers the IDE automatically over IntelliJ's
                built-in server; there is nothing to pair or paste.</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Private by design</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Listens on <b>localhost only</b> — never reachable from the network.</li>
            <li>Honors IntelliJ's <b>trusted projects</b>: untrusted projects are never navigated.</li>
            <li>Toggle it off anytime under <em>Settings → Tools → Jeffrey Microscope Plugin</em>; a
                disabled IDE is completely invisible to Microscope.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
            Requires a running Jeffrey Microscope instance. Learn more at
            <a href="https://jeffrey-analyst.cafe">jeffrey-analyst.cafe</a>.
        </p>
    ]]></description>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.java</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <httpRequestHandler implementation="cafe.jeffrey.ide.plugin.idea.JeffreyMicroscopeService"/>
        <applicationService serviceImplementation="cafe.jeffrey.ide.plugin.idea.ProjectRegistry"/>
        <applicationService serviceImplementation="cafe.jeffrey.ide.plugin.idea.settings.JeffreySettings"/>
        <applicationConfigurable parentId="tools"
                                 id="cafe.jeffrey.ide.plugin.idea.settings"
                                 instance="cafe.jeffrey.ide.plugin.idea.settings.JeffreyConfigurable"
                                 displayName="Jeffrey Plugin"/>
        <notificationGroup id="Jeffrey Microscope" displayType="BALLOON"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
